他在杀害那些在萨洛尼卡审判中
He's killing those who fucked up
陷害你和你朋友阿皮斯的人
you and your pal Apis in the Thessaloniki process.
可能是你以前组织的黑手党成员
It's probably someone from your former organization the Black Hand.
你难道看不出来迪米特里耶维奇和谋杀案没有任何关系吗？
Don't you realize that Dimitriyevich has nothing to do with the murders?
塔尼，他已经认罪了！
Tane, he has admitted the guilt!
如果迪米特里耶维奇有可能是无辜的
If there's any chance that Dimitriyevich is innocent,
我可以证明！
I can prove it!
他打电话给他儿子然后... 然后他就认罪了
He called his son and... Then he confessed everything.
我救了你儿子
I saved your son.
他和我在一起很安全
He's with me. Safe.
谁给你设的套？
Who set this up for you?
奥布拉德 · 萨夫科维奇
Obrad Savkovich.
送她出去
See the miss off.
我给你一份生意
I offer you a share in the business,
国家的保护和分销海洛因的安全路线
state protection and safe routes for the distribution of heroin.
我要杀了他
I will liquidate him.
不行! 他是科罗沙克的人
Don't! He is Koroshac's man.
我们还需要科罗沙克先生
And we will need Mr. Koroshac.
贝尔格莱德的局势迅速变得更加复杂
The situation in Belgrade is rapidly becoming more complicated,
尤其是对日夫科维奇将军
especially for General Zhivkovich.
他担任了多年内政部长
He was the Minister of the Interior for years.
他可不是个单纯的人
And he's not a naive man, at all.
巴尔图将直接从莫斯科前往贝尔格莱德
Bartu will come to Belgrade directly from Moscow.
国王将拒绝承认苏联主权
The king will refuse the recognition of the Soviet Union.
他们两个会一起炸毁日尔诺夫
The two of them will blow up Zhrnov together.
要找我的话就用这个
This is how you will find me.
波多黎各朗姆酒？
Puerto Rican rum?
我们的兄弟像狗一样死去，而你却袖手旁观
Our brothers are dying like dogs and you've done nothing about it.
我不杀那些罪有应得的人
I don't kill those who deserve it,
而是杀那些需要被杀的人
but those who need to be killed.
我卷入了..
I got involved in...
我得去个地方
I gotta go somewhere.
我需要你的帮助
I need one of your services.
安德拉 · 塔纳西耶维奇... 你必须杀了他
Andra Tanasiyevich... You have to kill him.
- 而这一切的幕后黑手... - 奥布拉德 · 萨瓦科维奇
- And the man behind everything... - Obrad Savkovich.
巴尔干半岛的阴影 第二季 第八集
BLACK SUN SEASON 2 EPISODE 08
尝尝吧
Taste it.
我酿造的白兰地
I make the brandy.
你想来点吗？
You want some?
找个地方躲起来，从农民那里买些梅子，接着酿白兰地...
Take shelter somewhere, buy plums from peasants, make brandy...
我会负担所有的费用
I'll finance everything.
你是从黑山来就是为了把我赶出我的城市的吗？
Did you come from Montenegro to dislodge me from my city?
不，我是让你躲起来
No, I'm telling you to take shelter
几个月，直到我掌管这个地方
for a few months until I manage here.
然后你再华丽回归
And then you'll come back on the white horse.
不可能，托马斯维奇
No way, Tomasovich.
看来你得杀了我了
Looks like you'll have to kill me.
我很乐意杀掉你
I would love to.
但我不能杀我的救命恩人
But I can't kill the man who saved my life.
你不打算告诉我是谁让你杀我的？
You're not going to tell me who asked you to kill me?
不，那不重要
No. It doesn't matter.
这很重要，托马斯维奇
It does matter, Tomasovich.
真的很重要
It does
我说不重要就是不重要
I'm telling you it doesn't.
如果我放你走，他会派别人来杀你
If I let you leave, he'll find someone else to kill you.
他不会的
He won't.
因为我会在那之前...
Because I'm going to kill...
杀掉他们所有人
all of them before that.
我要杀修道士
I'll kill the Monk
还有奥布拉德·萨夫科维奇
and Obrad Savkovich.
丹尼洛
Danilo...
之前你让我为你工作
once you asked me to work for you.
现在我邀请你跟我合作
Now I offer you to work together.
让我们联手杀了那个混蛋
Let's kill that shit.
为你的兄弟报仇
Let's avenge your brother
并且你可以轻而易举地掌管这座城市
and you'll get this city on a platter.
好了
Well...
要么你把手给我
Either give me your hand,
要么杀了我
or kill me,
要么你就去死吧
or go fuck yourself.
他说得对
He's right.
丹尼洛，我们做过很多事情
Danilo, you and I have done various things in our lives.
但是我们从来没有和人渣合作过
But we've never worked with the scum.
这白兰地很好喝，塔尼
This brandy is good, Tane.
你现在满意了吗？
Are you satisfied now?
塔尼是对的，但是你偏不听，坚持自己的观点
Tane was right, but no, you continued your own way.
你现在满意了吗？
Are you satisfied now?
他离开了这个世界... 一个好人，我们的朋友！
The man has left this world... A good man, our man!
不应该是这样的
That's not how it's done, Pletikosich.
你的学校狗屁都没教你
They didn't teach you anything in all those schools of yours...
塔尼所经历的那种学校，你永远也不会知道！
The kind of school Tane went through, you never will!
永远不会！
Never!
里面怎么样了？
How's it going inside?
怎么会变成这样...
How it can be...
- 不用了，谢谢 - 拿着！
- No, thanks. - Take it.
没有打斗的痕迹
There are no traces of the fight.
首先他是被毒死的
First, he was poisoned,
然后他... 死了
and then he... died.
他死了？
He died?
自杀
Suicide.
或者是谋杀，我们还不知道
Or murder, we don't know yet.
他随身带药了吗？
Did he have any medication with him?
是的
Yes.
- 是吗? - 是的，镇静剂
- He had? - Yes, tranquillizers.
他求我们把这药留给他
He begged us to leave it to him.
你为什么不告诉我？
Why didn't you tell me that?
也许他吹牛吹得太多忘记了
Maybe he forgot from bragging too much.
医生，拜托
Doctor, please.
大家听我说
Listen to me, everyone.
这是自杀
This is suicide.
我们还不能确定，因为...
We can't know that, because...
泽切维奇! 已经确定了
Zechevich! We can. And we know.
明白了吗？
Is that clear?
结案，罪犯自行了断
The case was resolved, the culprit judged himself.
就这样，你们可以走了
That's all, you can go.
坏消息？
Bad news?
迪米特里耶维奇？
Dimitriyevich?
你要我告诉他吗？
You want me to tell him?
我去吧
I will.
应该由我告诉他
I have to do it.
斯特拉辛加！
Strahinja!
下午好，塔尼！
Good afternoon, Tane!
探长！
Inspector!
什么事？
Yes?
这不是你的错
It's not your fault.
谁说是我的错了？
Who says it's my fault?
没有人
No one.
我只是觉得你不应该怀疑自己的决定
I just don't think you should doubt your decisions.
谁说我怀疑自己的决定？
Who says I doubt my decisions?
在我看来就是这样
That's how it seemed to me.
在你看来? ！
It seemed to you?!
你是什么? ！
And what are you?!
是巫师？还是警官？
Some sorcerer or inspector?
一个男人死了
It was a man who died,
不是流浪狗
not a stray dog.
而是贝尔格莱德最好的警察之一
One of the best Belgrade policemen.
他死在这里，死在在警局
And he died here, at Glavnjacha.
这就是问题所在
That's the point.
我认为迪米特里耶维奇有一个同伙
I think Dimitriyevich had an accomplice.
- 在警局内部? - 是的
- At Glavnjacha? - Yes.
也许是那个人杀了他
Maybe that person killed him.
我不知道，也许我不对...
I don't know, maybe I'm not right...
但我确定迪米特里耶维奇就是凶手
But I'm sure Dimitriyevich is the killer.
我不知道该怎么想了
I don't know what to think anymore.
但是我们有这么多证据...
But we have so much evidence...
指纹、证人、证词、假签名等等
Fingerprints, witness testimony, fake signatures...
而且他认罪了！
He confessed!
甚至连那个疯子拉杰科都认出了他！
Even that crazy Rajko recognized him!
那个疯子拉杰科怎么样了？
What happened to the crazy Rajko?
没什么，我们让他走了，他没有理由进监狱
Nothing, we let him go, there was no reason for him to be in jail.
你要去哪儿？
Where are you going?
我要..
I'm going to...
找到那个疯子拉杰科
find that crazy Rajko.
我和你一起去
I'll go with you.
你留在这里，把那个同伙揪出来
You stay here and try to find the accomplice.
南斯拉夫王国 贝尔格莱德 日尔诺夫 阿瓦拉
AVALA, ZHRNOV, BELGRADE, KINGDOM OF YUGOSLAVIA
楼梯在这里吗？
So the staircase will be here?
没错
That's right.
- 客人是从那边过来? - 是的
- Guests come from there? - Yes.
很好
Good.
我们将在这里招待客人
We'll accommodate the guests here.
没错
That's right.
- 周围会有人 - 是的，是的
- People will be around. - Yes, yes.
殿下和巴尔图安置在那里
We will place His Highness and Bartu up there.
并且演奏我们和法国国歌
Please, the orchestra should play our and the French anthem.
管弦乐队该放在哪里？
And where to put the orchestra?
我告诉过你，别问那些愚蠢的问题
I'll tell you, don't ask stupid questions,
先把地上这些泥巴解决掉
just solve this mud here.
少校，问题不大
Mr. Major, it will be fine.
跟我来！
Follow me!
亲爱的先生...
Dear sir...
你现在被任命为建筑经理了吗？
have you now been appointed to be the construction manager?
是的，亲王派我来的
Yes, the prince sent me.
由于最近发生的一些事件，工程进展很慢
The works are very late due to all the recent events.
所以这一切都会消失吗？
So, all of this is going to disappear, huh?
就是这样
That's how it goes.
旧的被拆掉，新的建起来
Old things are torn down to be replaced by new ones.
你不会相信的，但这叫做进步，亲爱的
You wouldn't believe it, but it's called progress, my dear.
这地方怪怪的
This place is weird.
每次我来，我都很紧张
Every time I come, I'm tense.
感觉脖子后面有风
It's like someone's breathing down my neck.
是的
Yeah.
说实话我讨厌那些迷信的废话
Honestly, I hate all that superstitious nonsense,
但我想我明白你的意思了
but I think I understand what you're trying to say.
这些石头有些不祥之处
There's something sinister about these stones.
请允许我说，我对你的草稿感到惊讶
Please, let me say that I was surprised by your drafts.
什么意思？
What do you mean?
对不起，我完全不懂，但我期望更多..
I'm sorry, I'm completely ignorant, but I expected more...
怎么说呢... 更乐观，对吧？
How to put it... More optimism, right?
为了南斯拉夫的荣耀，为了我们的国家... 诸如此类
To the glory of Yugoslavia, our nations... something like that.
但是你的草稿..
But this draft of yours...
是个坟墓，不是吗？
It's a tomb, isn't it?
我说错了吗？
Am I wrong?
也许吧
Maybe.
时间会证明一切
Time will tell.
打扰一下
Excuse me,
你同意殿下在这里发言吗？
do you agree that His Highness should speak from here?
- 当然! - 好的！
Absolutely! Yes!
你听到了，把这清理干净
You heard it, so straighten all this.
- 好的 - 跟我来
- Okay. - Follow me.
你要走了吗？
Are you going already?
我必须走，我有工作要做
I have to, I have work to do.
你什么都不用做
You don't have to do anything.
请留下
Stay, please.
玛雅，我们得回到现实世界
Maya, we have to go back to the real world.
恐怕现实世界
I'm afraid the real world
可以结束这一切
can end all of this.
我害怕如果我留下来会发生什么
And I'm afraid of what will happen if I stay.
逃跑？
Running away?
你害怕坠入爱河吗？
Are you afraid of falling in love?
不..
No...
太晚了
it's too late for that.
保加利亚边境 马其顿 德拉切村
Dramche village, Macedonia, Bulgaria border
一，二，三！
One, two, three!
- 是一百吗? - 是的，一百
- Is it a hundred? - Yes, a hundred.
- 你说你要两个的 - 快点，给我！
- You said you'll take two. - Come on, give me!
给你，让我试试
Here you are. Let me try now.
来吧，你来
Come on, you put it.
- 给我 - 特纳瓦茨！
- Give me. - Trnavatz!
- 什么事? - 格兹姆，过来！
- Yes? - Gezim, come here!
- 来了 - 货准备好了吗？
- Tell me. - Are the goods ready?
是的，我们该怎么处理呢？
Yes, what should we do with it?
尽可能多带点去贝尔格莱德，好吗？
Pack as much as you can and go to Belgrade, okay?
宪兵怎么办？
What about the gendarmes?
克鲁姆，过来！
Krume, come here!
什么事？
Yes?
你也去贝尔格莱德
You're going to Belgrade, too.
- 好的 - 选一条路，好吗？
- Okay. - Take one of your paths, okay?
好的
Okay.
这是给宪兵的
This is for the gendarmes.
这些够吗？
Is it enough?
我还可以用剩下的钱去大保健
I can also get a massage for this.
- 太好了! - 完美
- Great! - With a happy ending.
告诉黑山的人，我们不能再等了
Tell the Montenegrin that we can no longer wait,
他必须不惜一切代价解决这个问题
and that he must do whatever it takes to solve this situation.
快点，去吧，你这个混蛋！
Come on, get outta here, you motherfucker!
迪姆切，过来
Dimche, come here.
快点！
Come on!
克鲁姆，你要去哪里？
Krume, where are you going?
你问那么多干什么? ！
What do you care?!
管好你自己的事
Mind your own business.
- 我说什么了? 过来! - 多少？
- What did I say? Come here! - How many?
一个？
One?
加油，赞内，我们走! 继续出拳！
Come on, Tzane, let's go! Keep punching!
谁赢了，沙袋赢还是你赢？
Who wins, the sack or you?
平局
It's a draw, for the sack.
看到了吗? 和米兰在一起不容易! 来吧，迪姆切
See? It's not easy with Milan! Come on, Dimche.
嘿，冠军! 你在练习，是吗？
Hey, champ! You're practising, huh?
是的
Yeah.
你就是这样打女孩的吗？
Is that how you hit girls?
不！
No!
我只会亲吻女孩
I kiss them.
你怎么亲的？
How do you kiss them?
要我给你演示一下吗？
Do you want me to show you?
不要
No.
他们在干什么？
What are they doing?
制造毒品
Making drugs.
- 你试过吗? - 没有，我是个运动员
- Have you ever tried it? - No, I'm an athlete.
我对那个不感兴趣
I'm not interested in that.
我对什么都感兴趣
I'm interested in everything.
- 你想试试吗? - 不！
- Do you want to try it? - No!
毒品是给傻瓜用的
Drugs are for fools.
我就是个傻瓜！
I am a fool!
你好！
Hello!
你好
Hello.
警察？
Police, huh?
斯坦科 · 普莱蒂科西奇督察
Inspector Stanko Pletikosich.
你能告诉我拉杰科是否住在这里吗？
Can you please tell me if Rajko lived here?
是的，就在这个房间里
Yes, right in this room.
他真的在日尔诺夫上杀了人吗？
Is it true that he killed that guy on Zhrnov?
显然不是，我们放他走了
Apparently not. We let him go.
- 他来过这里吗? - 没有，孩子
- Did he come here? - No, sonny.
自从你逮捕他后就没人见过他了
No one has seen him since you arrested him.
这是什么地方？
Where is this place?
我想那是一所孤儿院，他曾经在那里当过老师
I think it's an orphanage where he used to work as a teacher.
你介意我..
Do you mind if I...
什么？
What?
去看看
To take a look.
好吧
Fine.
“致我的同伴拉杰科——阿比斯"
"To my companion Rajko." Apis
不，谋杀萨夫科维奇不是解决之道
No, the murder of Savkovich is not the solution.
我不管，我要杀了他
I don't care. I'll kill him.
即使你设法杀了他，你得不到任何好处
Even if you manage to kill him, you won't achieve anything.
这个阴谋的范围要广得多
That conspiracy is much broader.
我们需要找出他的同伙和他的计划
We need to find out who he works with and what his plans are.
我们要怎么知道？难道让他告诉我们吗？
How do we find out? Should we ask him to tell us?
不，我们不会向他要任何东西
No, we won't ask him for anything.
我们绑架他
We'll kidnap him.
- 别这样玛雅，我是认真的 - 我也是
- Come on, Maya, I'm serious. - Me, too.
还记得我的斯洛文尼亚朋友，国王卫队的科斯马奇少校吗？
Remember my Slovenian friend, Major Kosmach from the King's Guard?
他怎么了？
What about him?
他会帮我们的
He'll help us.
大家都在等待日夫科维奇将军的辞职
Everyone is waiting for the resignation of General Zhivkovich.
这就是我们引诱他的方法
That's how we're going to lure him.
你去找你的黑山朋友
You just find that Montenegrin of yours.
等我消息
And wait for me to call you.
祝你用餐愉快，小钢炮！
Enjoy your meal, Diesel!
谢谢
Thanks.
怎么回事? ！
What happened?!
雅娜在里面！
Yana's inside!
卡住了！
It's stuck!
快点，雅娜在里面！
Come on, Yana is inside!
雅娜！
Yana!
- 雅娜! - 怎么了？
- Yana! - What happened?
雅娜在里面，雅娜！
Yana's inside! Yana!
谁在那里? ，雅娜? ！
Who's there? Yana?!
把门砸了，快点！
Break it, come on!
嘿！嘿！你要去哪儿? ！
Hey, hey, hey! Where are you going?!
让我试试! 让开！
Let me try! Move!
快点！
Come on!
- 打破它! - 雅娜！
- Break it! - Yana!
她还活着吗？
Is she alive?
- 把她放在这儿! - 拿点水来！
- Put her here! - Bring some water!
- 水! - 放松，放松！
- Water! - Easy, easy!
孩子! 能听见我说话吗? 你没事吧？
Hey, sonny! Can you hear me? Are you okay?
你还好吗？
Are you okay?
天啊！兰卡... 你做了什么？
Jesus, Ranka... What have you done?
你为什么不及时告诉我们？
Why didn't you tell us in time?
我做不到
I couldn't.
我很害怕
I was scared.
我为什么要给他那该死的刺刀？
Why did I give him the fucking bayonet?
他告诉我他喜欢收集军用装备
He told me he likes to collect that military shit.
他们不费吹灰之力就把你玩弄于股掌之间
They would fuck you over without a dick.
你为了一杯酒就被耍了，那又怎么样？
You get fucked over for a drink, so what?
莫德林是我的表弟，他这么做没关系
Maudlin is my cousin, it's okay for him to do it.
我发誓我不知道那是个圈套！
I swear I didn't know about that set-up!
我只是想赚点钱
I just wanted to make some money.
晚上好
Good evening.
他来了！
Oh, here he is!
你想再逮捕一个人吗？
You want to arrest someone again, huh?
我来是想说我错了
I came to say that I was wrong.
对不起
I am sorry.
你是应该对不起
Well, you should be.
再见
Goodbye.
斯坦科，等等！
Stanko, wait!
- 过来 - 不了
- Come here. - It's okay.
过来喝一杯！
Come here for a drink!
然后呢？
And?
我们又回到了原点
Here we are again at the beginning.
在我看来更像是末日
It looks more like the end to me.
走着瞧
We'll see.
对不起，我不相信你
Sorry I didn't trust you.
让你卷入这件事..
And involved you in this...
还因为我变成了傻瓜
And especially because I turned out to be a fool.
你不必为后者向我道歉
You don't have to apologize to me for the latter.
你和我都是天生的傻瓜
You and I were born fools.
一个无辜的人死了
An innocent man died.
你是对的，这背后还有
You were right, there's someone much bigger
更有权势的人
and more powerful behind this.
在这背后的是
Behind this are people
想要消灭这个国家的人
who want to erase this country...
改写历史... 把一切都搞砸
To change its history... And screw everything up.
那些人是谁？
Who are those people?
那些想杀死国王
Those who want to kill the king
把他的痕迹抹掉的人
and erase everything along with him.
想要创造一个新时代的人们
People who want to create a new age.
奥布拉德 · 萨夫科维奇，阿里姆皮耶 · 米里奇
Obrad Savkovich, Alimpiye Mirich
天知道还有谁
and God knows who else.
你有证据吗？
Do you have evidence for that?
即使我有，你会怎么处理它们？
Even if I had, what would you do with them?
前任和现任警官能对他们做什么？
What can a former and a current police officer do to them?
他们拥有一切
They hold everything.
他们就是一切
They are everything.
我们能做什么？
What can we do?
我们可以看着
We can just watch.
我们只能这么做
That's all we can do,
没错
That's right.
或者..
Or...
我们可以联合起来搞垮这帮人
We can team up and fuck up the gang.
- 你和我? - 你和我
- You and me? - You and me.
我们用他们的方式来攻击这些人渣
Let's hit the scum the same way he does.
没有规则，没有慈悲
No rules, no mercy.
无论如何... 直到最后
However we can... Until the end.
你和我？
You and me?
是的，我们会有更多战友
Yes, and there'll be more of us.
你是认真的吗？
Are you serious?
我从来没有这么认真过
I've never been more serious.
等等
Wait...
你想让我们无视法律
You want us to screw up the laws,
国家和我们的生活...
the state, our lives...
然后向他们宣战？
And declare war on them?
我准备好了
I am ready,
但前提是你得跟我一起
but only if you're with me.
和你一起？
With you?
一直都是
Always.
那么...
Well, then...
战争？
War?
战争
War.
南斯拉夫王国 达尔马提亚
HVAR, DALMATIA KINGDOM OF YUGOSLAVIA
米里奇先生！
Mr. Mirich!
科罗沙克先生！
Mr. Koroshac!
- 你说你会来的时候... - 怎么？
- When you said you would come... - Yes?
我在考虑是否应该接待你
I was thinking whether to receive you.
为什么？
Why?
好吧，亲爱的先生，你为什么来？
All right, dear sir, why did you come?
告诉我
Tell me,
你做了多久
how long have you been
内政部长？
the Minister of the Interior?
十年了，对吧？
Ten years, right?
差不多吧，怎么了？
More or less, yes. Why?
你要不要考虑...
Would you like to return...
给亲王殿下的政府做内政部长？
to the government of His Royal Highness?
得了吧！
Come on!
拜托，米里奇先生！
Oh, please, Mr. Mirich!
你什么时候开始组建政府了？
Since when do you form a government?
科罗沙克先生，请坐
Mr. Koroshac, please have a seat.
日夫科维奇将军将会辞职...
The resignation of General Zhivkovich...
几乎可以肯定
is almost certain.
- 真的? - 是的
- Really? - Yes.
怎么，他要退休了？
Why, is he retiring?
可以这么说
In some way.
这个国家需要你这样的人
This country needs people like you.
清廉，有远见
Immaculate, with a vision.
至于你的黑山朋友
And as for that Montenegrin of yours,
我已经把他逼到了墙角
whom I backed into a corner...
这是可以解决的
That can be solved.
我们愿与你方开展互惠互利的业务合作
We offer you business cooperation for mutual benefit.
你刚说的这些，我想...
All of that, I suppose,
都是萨夫科维奇先生的主意吧
is the idea of your Mr. Savkovich.
我看你消息灵通，是的
I see you are well informed. Yes.
这就是我们的提议
That's our offer.
是的，我明白
Yes, I understand.
恐怕..
I'm afraid...
恐怕奥布拉德 · 萨夫科维奇和我
Obrad Savkovich and I...
对未来没有同样的憧憬
don't have the same vision for the future, you know.
我是基督徒
I'm a Christian.
而他...
And he...
我应该把这当作拒绝吗？
Should I take this as a rejection?
哦，不，不! 放松
Oh, no, no! Easy.
放松
Easy.
“早晨比晚上聪明”
"Morning is wiser than the evening."
我需要点时间思考
I need some time to think.
我明天早上答复你
I'll let you know tomorrow morning.
我明白
I understand.
明天早上
Until tomorrow morning.
请打电话给科斯马奇
Please call Kosmach.
告诉他我祝福他
Tell him he has my blessing.
- 日沃因! - 督察先生！
- Zhivoyin! - Mr. inspector!
我们能私下谈谈吗？
Can we talk in private?
当然，去吧！
Of course, yes! Come on!
请坐
Have a seat.
- 你想来一杯吗? - 好的
- Would you like one, huh? - Yes.
- 给你 - 谢谢
- Here you are. - Thanks.
你多大岁数了？
How old are you?
很老了，督察
Too old, inspector.
- 你什么时候退休? - 退休！
- When will you retire? - Retire?!
我有三个孩子
I have three children.
用那点可怜的养老金怎么养活这么多孩子呢？
How can I feed so many children with such a miserable pension?
- 你儿子呢? - 什么？
- And your son? - What?
他会上军事学院吗？
Will he go to the military academy?
看来你消息很灵通啊？
I see you're well informed, huh?
所以我才是督察
That's why I'm the inspector.
太对了！
Exactly!
如果我们存点钱
If we save some money,
他可以成为一个绅士
he can be a gentleman.
如果没有，他就永远都是一个宪兵
If not, he can always be a gendarme.
都不需要上学
He doesn't need school for that,
拼命工作就行了
just to bend over backwards.
这是一项艰巨的工作，督察
It's a hard work, inspector.
尤其是拼命工作的部分
Especially the part with bending over backwards.
你有多少次为前任局长拼命工作？
How many times you bent over backwards for the former chief?
给迪米特里耶维奇？
For Dimitriyevich?
不，给他工作不是很辛苦，我们只是..
No, the work wasn't too hard, we just...
绕过了法律和行政条款
Bypassed the law and the rules of the service.
我们都这样，不是吗？
Well, we all do that, don't we?
我们不知道，日沃因
We don't, Zhivoyin.
不是所有人
Not all of us.
我可不这么认为
I wouldn't say that's true.
是的
It is.
谁拜访了迪米特里耶维奇？
Who visited Dimitriyevich?
他没有多少访客...
He didn't have many visits...
你知道我在问你什么
You know what I'm asking you.
我不知道，有记录，我没有看..
I don't know, there's a record, I didn't look at it...
迪米特里耶维奇去世前，谁去看过他？
Who visited Dimitriyevich just before his death?
我不知道
I don't know.
你知道的
You know, Zhivoyin.
你很清楚警局里发生了什么
You know very well what's going on in Glavnjacha.
你很清楚
And you know very well
被停职的宪兵就不能养活他的家人了
that a suspended gendarme cannot support his family.
什么意思？
What do you mean suspended?
触犯了法律的人还怎么继续服役？
How can someone who has broken the law stay in the service?
我没犯法，我..
I didn't break a law, I...
你犯法了
You did, Zhivoyin.
很容易就能证明
And I'll prove it easily.
你会被解雇的
You'll be fired.
明白吗？
Understand?
你的余生
For the rest of your life,
就只能在家劈柴
you'll chop wood in mansions.
你儿子也不会成为军官
And your son won't be an officer.
你想要什么？
What do you want?
费利克斯同志！
Comrade Felix!
是彼特鲁列夫斯基，我告诉过你无数次了
It's Petrusevski, I told you a million times.
没人能听见
Nobody can hear us.
总有一天会有人听到，那时候我就不得不弄死你了
One day someone will hear, so I'll have to cut off your head.
给你
Here you are.
美国货？
American?
去他们的，怎么回事？
Fuck them. What's going on?
丹妮卡同志想见你
Comrade Danica wanted to see you.
- 她会见我的 - 不不！
- She'll see me. - No, no!
她让我在你到达时给她打电话
She told me to call her when you arrive
等她过来，她有事要告诉你
and to wait for her, she has something to tell you.
给她打电话
Well, call her.
怎么了，丹妮卡？
What is it, Danica?
我们私下说
This isn't for everyone's ears.
这是昨天从莫斯科发来的，很紧急
This arrived from Moscow yesterday. It's urgent.
操！
Fuck!
- 还有别的吗? - 不止这些
- Did anything else arrive? - Not just that.
南斯拉夫确定不会承认苏联主权
Yugoslavia definitely won't recognize the Soviet Union.
因为这很愚蠢
Because it's stupid.
这对我们意味着什么？
What does it mean for us?
一切都变成了地狱，一切都在改变
That everything has gone to hell and that everything is changing.
还有一件事
There's one more thing.
快点，有人在等我们
Come on, they're waiting for us.
我给你泡了茶
I made you some tea.
谢谢你
Thank you.
要我给你做点别的吃的吗？
Do you want me to make you something else to eat?
不必了，你更擅长解剖尸体
Please don't. You're better at dissecting corpses.
至少尸体不会胡说八道
At least they don't talk nonsense.
我们这个室友的生活还不错
We're not doing badly in this roommate's life.
这是什么？
What's this?
我在找拉杰科
I'm looking for Rajko...
他在日尔诺夫发现了第一个受害者
He found the first victim at Zhrnov.
自从我们放了他，他就消失得无影无踪
Since we've released him, he disappeared without a trace.
他是那个戴着白帽子的人
He's the one wearing the white hat.
你为什么要找他？
Why are you looking for him?
我不知道，我感觉他和这个案子的关联比我想象的要大
I don't know, I have a feeling he's more connected than we think.
好像我漏掉了一个连接的点
It's like I'm missing one detail to connect.
我知道这个地方
I know this place.
战争孤儿之家
The War Orphans' Home.
我在那里领小佩塔尔出来
I picked up little Petar from there.
拉杰科曾在那里工作过
Rajko used to work there.
我去档案馆找找看
I'll try to find something in the archive.
我认识那些人
I know those people.
你躲在我的房子里，还想扮侦探
You're hiding in my house, and you want to play detective.
不可能
No way.
你到底想不想知道？
Well, do you want to know or not?
她什么时候走的？
When did she leave?
你走后她就没回来过
She hasn't come back since you left.
她甚至没有回家，我查过了
She didn't even go home, I checked.
好吧
There you go.
也许..
Well, maybe...
什么? 告诉我
What? Tell me.
我不知道
I don't know.
快说！
Tell me!
也许她去找她前男友了
Maybe she went to her ex.
你从哪儿来的消息？
Where did you get that?
我在俱乐部看到他们在一起
I saw them together at the club.
什么? ！
What?!
你也和她在一起
You were with her once, too.
这是真的
It's true.
我见过他们几次..
I saw them a few times...
他们似乎相处得很好
They seemed to get along well.
你现在才告诉我？
And you're just telling me this now?
该死的! 你这个混蛋！
Goddammit! And you motherfucker!
- 什么? - 别问什么！
- What? - Don't ask what!
我以为你知道! 我怎么知道如果..
I thought you knew! How do I know if...
你平时什么都知道，但现在你不知道了！
Normally you know everything, but now you don't!
我也不知道我需不需要让你知道她的事
I didn't know I needed to let you know about her either.
马诺伊洛，找到她
Manoylo, find her.
你知道该怎么做
You know what to do.
出去
Get out of here.
出去! 出去！
Out! Get out!
这不是我的错！
It's not my fault!
你喝酒吗，孩子？
Do you drink, boy?
对不起，探长
Sorry, inspector.
不多
Not much.
这是什么意思? 你喝还是不喝？
What does it mean? You drink or not?
嗯...喝也不喝
Well, both.
啥？！
Damn!
你们这一代都这样？
What kind of generation are you?
你连喝不喝酒这么简单的事情都决定不了
You can't decide on such a simple thing as a drink.
你来找我干什么？
Why did you come?
我不想让你误会
I don't want you to misunderstand me,
我知道你不喜欢我...
I know you don't like me...
不是我不喜欢你..。
It's not that I don't like you...
你只是有点...欠操
You're just a bit... unfucked.
但你有胆量
But you have balls,
我注意到了
I noticed that.
你是最后一个去看迪米特里耶维奇的人
You were the last to visit Dimitriyevich.
我怎么知道？
How could I know that, huh?
宪兵知道
The gendarmes know.
日沃因说的？
Zhivoyin said it?
我不会告诉你是谁说的
I won't tell anyone.
行吧
Well, thank you.
普莱蒂科西奇督察和我最近关系不太好
Inspector Pletikosich and I have not been on good terms lately.
他独立行动
He works on his own.
让我问你一个问题，孩子
Let me ask you a question, sonny.
你为什么要进警察局？
Why are you in the police?
你是觉得我太软弱了？
You mean because I'm so soft?
我没别的意思，我只是问问
I don't mean anything. I'm asking.
探长，你信教吗？
Are you a religious man, inspector?
和信仰有什么关系呢？
What does it matter now?
一向与信仰有关
It always does.
信仰引导我
You see, faith leads me through life.
真的吗？
Really?
我看你不是那样的
You don't look like that to me.
我一直对人性很感兴趣
I've always been interested in human nature.
人性的阴暗面
Its dark side.
为什么人会失去自己神圣的一面？
Why does a man lose that divine part of himself?
那你来对地方了，孩子
Then you're in the right place, sonny.
我知道
I know.
我还知道你在追踪凶手
I also know you're on the trail of a killer.
真正的凶手
The real killer.
我不知道迪米特里耶维奇有没有告诉你，或者是你自己决定的
I don't know if Dimitriyevich told you or you concluded for yourself,
但我觉得你在给凶手设套
but I think you're setting a trap for him.
我想成为你计划的一部分
I want to be a part of it.
我想帮忙，把凶手捉拿归案
I want to help. To arrest him.
你的想象力真丰富，孩子
You have a vivid imagination, son.
即使你是对的，你也不能逮捕那样的人
Even if you're right, you can't arrest people like that.
相信我
Trust me.
我不理解
I don't get it.
这是唯一正确的选择
It's the only right thing to do.
可能吧，你可以走了
Probably. You can go now.
我还有工作要做
I have some work to do.
你错了
You're wrong.
安德鲁
Andrew.
近来可好？
How are you?
主教大人还好吗？
How is the bishop?
不错
Fine.
我们真要这么做吗？
Are we going to do this?
我为什么会同意做这样的事？
Why do you think I would agree to something like this?
因为萨夫科维奇把我们逼到了绝境
Because Savkovich backed us into a corner.
我们的每个计划都失败了
Each of our plans failed.
如果这个问题不能尽快解决，我将会返回美国
If this is not resolved quickly, I will return to America.
萨夫科维奇是个谨慎的人
Savkovich is a cautious man.
他的房子就像一座堡垒，我们无论如何都接近不了他
His house is like a fortress, we can't reach him in any way.
但你可以
You can.
如果我们让他承认这个阴谋
If we make him confess the conspiracy,
所有的功劳都归科罗沙克先生
all the credit would go to Mr. Koroshac.
他的未来会大不相同
His future would look quite different.
将是一次华丽的回归
It would be a big comeback.
你确定吗？
Are you sure?
如果不确定我就不会给你打电话了
I wouldn't call you if I wasn't.
玛雅调查了银行里所有的文件
Maya asked for all the papers from the bank.
这并不意味着她能理解这其中的联系
It doesn't mean she understood the connection yet.
即使她不理解，她也会很快就会理解的
Even if she didn't, she'll figure it out quickly.
非常快
Very quickly.
她是个聪明的女人
She's a smart woman.
我是一个理性的人
And I'm a rational man.
我向你保证在没有理由的时候不用担心
I assured you not to worry when there was no reason for it
并且告诉你我们应该继续执行计划..
and told you we should continue with our plan...
但这次不同
But this is different.
那个女人很危险
That woman is dangerous.
她会毁了我们的计划
She'll ruin our plan.
然后呢？
And?
你有什么建议？
What do you suggest?
她必须消失
She must disappear.
我会处理玛雅的事
I'll take care of Maya.
我该如何理解这句话呢？
How should I understand that?
玛雅不会阻止我们的计划
Maya won't stand in our way.
出来！
Come out!
一切都准备好了吗？
Is everything ready?
是的老大
Yes, boss.
他为什么不来？
Why didn't he come?
我们约好在家里见面，但他没有来
We were supposed to meet at our place, but he didn't come.
他怎么了？
What's up with him?
这就是我想说的
That's what I wanted to tell you.
他最近怪怪的
He's been weird lately.
他总是很奇怪，这不是什么新鲜事
He's always been weird, that's nothing new.
你说的”怪”是什么意思”？
What do you mean by "weird"?
他讲了一些奇怪的故事
He tells some strange stories,
我什么都不明白
I don't understand anything.
他让你把工作室烧了，对吧？
He told you to put the atelier on fire, right?
他让我把它炸掉
He asked me to blow it up.
我勉强说服他炸掉不合适
I barely convinced him it wasn't smart.
恐怕他已经开始独立行动了
I'm afraid he started working on his own.
胡说，他听我的
Nonsense. He listens to me.
他总是听我的
He always listened to me.
我只是说在我看来
I'm just saying how it seems to me.
好了，我会处理的
Okay, I'll take care of that.
你可以走了，在我吩咐之前什么也别做
You can go and don't do anything until I call you.
明白了吗？
Is that clear?
如果他打电话给我怎么办？
What if he calls me?
听起来你好像很怕他
You sound like you're afraid of him.
战争孤儿之家
THE WAR ORPHANS' HOME
你把档案管理得很好
You run the archive really well.
我尽力了
Well, I do my best.
拉杰科在这里工作了很长时间吗？
Could you tell me if Rajko worked here for a long time?
我来的时候他就在这儿了
He was already here when I came,
战争开始就在这里，他是个伟大的老师，各方面都是
he's been here since the war, a great teacher, in every way.
肯定有很多伟大的老师
Well, there must have been a lot of them.
是的，但他是个例外
Yes, but he was exceptional.
即使离开了医院，他还是照顾院里的孩子
He took care of our attendants even after leaving the institution.
他会帮助他们找工作或者供他们上学
He would find them a job or money for schooling.
这可不容易
That's not easy.
我们很幸运，有几个非常慷慨的赞助人
We were lucky to have a couple of really generous patrons,
有些人已经帮助我们很多年了，比如萨夫科维奇先生
some have been helping us for years, such as Mr. Savkovich.
奥布拉德 · 萨夫科维奇？
Obrad Savkovich?
是的，新时代的老板
Yes, the owner of the New Age.
你有他资助过的孩子名单吗？
Do you have the names of the children he helped?
当然，让我看看我把它放哪儿了..
Of course, let me see where I put it...
这里！
Oh, here it is!
- 给你 - 谢谢
- Here you are. - Thanks.
谢谢你
Thank you.
萨夫科维奇先生总是帮助我们
Mr. Savkovich always helps us.
无论何时我们有什么需要，都会打电话给他
Whenever we need something, we call him.
- 天啊! - 怎么了？
- Oh, my God! - What?
小姐，发生了什么...
Miss, is there something...
对不起，我得走了
Excuse me, I have to go.
小姐！
Miss!
我该拿你怎么办，玛雅？
What should I do with you, Maya?
这不是游戏
This is not a game.
这是有规则的
There are rules.
有限度的
And there are limits.
如果你违背了规则，你就完了
If you cross them, you're gone.
永远消失了
You disappear forever.
去他妈的生命
Fuck that life.
如果不能突破界限
If you can't push boundaries,
如果你不能把所有的事情都当成问题
if you can't call everything into a question,
那活着还有什么意思？
then why live?
你是..
You are...
一个危险的女人
A dangerous woman.
就像你一样
Just like you.
对我来说很危险
Dangerous for me.
这就是你把我排除在外的原因吗？
Is that why you excluded me from everything?
孤立我
Left me on the side.
而且你显然也不想再让我参与进来
And you obviously have no intention of including me in again.
你不相信我？
You don't believe me?
你相信我吗？
Do you believe me?
现在怎么办？
Now what?
小心
Beware.
小心你吗？
Of you, too?
尤其是要小心我
Especially of me.
庆祝已经结束了？
The celebration is already over?
你还想喝点别的吗？
Do you want something else to drink?
是的
Yes.
波多黎各朗姆酒
Puerto Rican rum.
少校！
Mr. Major!
天一黑你就直接去奥布拉德·萨夫科维奇的别墅
When it gets dark, you go straight to the villa of Obrad Savkovich.
他不会怀疑你的
Savkovich won't doubt you,
他知道你是保罗亲王的贴身卫兵
he knows you as a member of Prince Paul's guard.
要清楚直接，但不需要说服他
Be clear and direct, but don't convince him,
你只是在传达信息
you're just conveying a message.
我们会在科舒特尼亚克等他
We'll wait for them in Koshutnjak.
到时候那里没有车
There's no traffic at that time.
我们在那里设下埋伏
We'll set up an ambush there.
只杀安保人员
We only shoot at security.
要留萨夫科维奇活口
Savkovich must stay alive.
是的，但我不明白
Yes, but I don't get it.
- 萨夫科维奇先生...-怎么？
- Mr. Savkovich... - Yes?
这件事极为重要，而且十分紧急
The matter is of the utmost importance and quite urgent.
少校...
Mr. Major...
国王卫队和我有什么关系？
What has the King's Guard got to do with me?
我是保罗亲王卫兵
I come from Prince Paul.
亲王需要见你
He needs you.
日夫科维奇将军辞职了
General Zhivkovich resigned.
我要见萨夫科维奇先生
I have to see Mr. Savkovich.
在这儿等着
Wait here.
还没有公布消息
It has not been revealed yet,
但是保罗亲王想尽快见到你
but Prince Paul would like to see you as soon as possible.
为什么是我？
Why me?
我想他是要给你什么东西
I think he wants to offer you something.
我不能再多说什么了
I can't say anything more about it.
警官，萨夫科维奇先生有约
Inspector, Mr. Savkovich has a visit.
我必须见他
I have to see him.
找我有什么事吗？
How can I help you?
我是泽切维奇督察，重案组的
Inspector Zechevich, crime offences.
萨夫科维奇先生，你被捕了！
Mr. Savkovich, you're under arrest!
什么？
What?
- 把枪放下! - 别动！
- Put that down! - Don't touch the weapon!
- 警官，把枪放下! - 少校！
- Inspector, put the gun down! - Major!
别管这事
Stay out of this.
萨夫科维奇先生
Mr. Savkovich,
你因涉嫌多起谋杀案而被捕
you're under arrest for multiple murders...
听着！
Listen!
我是国王卫队的科斯马奇少校
I am Major Kosmach of the King's Guard.
萨夫科维奇先生要和我一起去皇宫
Mr. Savkovich goes with me to the palace.
我不知道你在干什么，但是把枪放下
I don't know what you're doing, but put the gun down
趁我还可以忘记你的名字之前赶紧离开
and get out of here while I'm still ready to forget your name.
孩子，别傻了！
Boy, don't be a fool!
我们走吗？
Are we going?
他哪儿也去不了
He's not going anywhere.
你差点毁了整个计划
You almost fucked us all up.
他们在给你设套，奥布拉德
They're setting you up, Obrad.
清醒一点
Pull yourself together.
我们失败了
We failed.
他看穿了我们的计划
He saw through us.
他们知道是我们干的
They know it's us.
现在没有回头路了
There's no going back now. We'll go to the end.
好吧
Okay...
战争开始了
The war has begun.